[Music]
We're no strangers to
love. You know the rules and so do
I. I feel commitments from what I'm
thinking
of. You wouldn't get this from any other
guy. I just want to tell you how I'm
feeling. Got to make you understand.
Never going to give you up. I'm going to
let you down. I'm going to run around
and desert you. I'm going to make
you say goodbye.
Tell a lie and hurt
you. We've known each other for so
long. Your heart's been aching, but
you're too shy to say we don't know
what's been going
on. We know the game and we're going to
play. If you ask me how I'm
feeling, don't tell me your truth. to
see. I will give
you
around
you. I will say
goodbye and hurt you. I will give
[Music]
you
around you. I will leave you. I will say
goodbye and hurt you.
Never going to give. Never going to
give.
We've known each other for so long.
Your heart's been aching, but you're too
shy to say it. We both know what's been
going
on. We know the game and we're going to
play it. I just want to tell you how I'm
feeling. Got to make you understand.
Never going to give you up. Never going
to let you down. Never going to run
around and desert you. Heat.
[Music]
Heat. Heat. Heat.
Never going to tell a lie and hurt you.
Never going to give you up. Never going
to let you down. Never going to run
around and desert you. Never going to
make you cry. Never going to say
goodbye. Never going to say goodbye.