many of you have probably seen my\h
recent appearance on Jubilee if you\h\h
haven't definitely check it out it's linked\h
in the description but the response has been\h\h
weird i've gotten some of the strangest\h
comments I've ever gotten in my career\h\h
while on social media and we're going to\h
talk about that but first let me give you\h\h
a little behind the scenes of what happened\h
in order to make this debate actually happen
i was watching Jubilee and saw a 20 verse one\h
episode and I said "Wow wouldn't it be a good\h\h
idea if it was a doctor verse antiaxer?" So I\h
had Sam shoot them an email and recommend the\h\h
idea for an episode and actually volunteer to be\h
the one in the middle they love the idea and they\h\h
said that they would absolutely be interested\h
in doing it so we went and right away started\h\h
scheduling it sam and I flew ourselves out to Los\h
Angeles where they filmed these episodes and the\h\h
participants didn't even know I was coming so that\h
was completely news to them i walk out into this\h\h
circle lights are on cameras already rolling i get\h
like a few giggles some applause some groans feel\h\h
totally nervous being in this cold environment\h
get into this uncomfy chair which impacted my\h\h
posture and we'll talk about that in a bit i was\h
actually surprised by the diversity of people not\h\h
based on their demographics but based on their\h
beliefs about vaccines there were people who were\h\h
vehemently antivaccine you could sense it from\h
them they got emotional there were individuals\h\h
who just had questions there were some people\h
that were skeptical of certain vaccines but not\h\h
other vaccines others were involved in legal\h
battles surrounding vaccines so it was such a\h\h
diverse group of people but what I will say that\h
they all had in common was they were all pretty\h\h
polite and nice to me and that was very welcome\h
and I very much appreciated that i even called\h\h
it out during the debate when it comes to how I\h
was feeling during the debate i just wanted to\h\h
make sure I was saying everything accurately so I\h
spoke more slowly than I would watching a Grey's\h\h
Anatomy or the pit reaction i was very careful to\h
make sure that I was presented accurate info that\h\h
I didn't misspeak on things to very clearly and\h
confidently say I don't know as much as I could\h\h
to show that you have to be transparent and to\h
also own the failures of past mistakes that the\h\h
medical community has made because guess what we\h
made those and a lot of the comments that came in\h\h
when the debate went live was people being very\h
thankful and kind to me calling me a saint i'm\h\h
a better person than they are cuz they would have\h
gotten really mad and what that taught me was that\h\h
people are very angry and emotional and I get that\h
but at the same time it told me how much people\h\h
don't know about what doctors actually do we spend\h
hours every single day doing our best to educate\h\h
patients on topics that they're not familiar with\h
that they've learned some misinformation about\h\h
that they're perhaps very passionate culturally\h
about and we have to approach that with a very\h\h
empathetic patient mindset so what you saw on\h
camera was what happens behind closed doors during\h\h
a doctor patient interaction i just can't show\h
those because of patient privacy but in reality\h\h
that is the type of empathetic listening that\h
happens when a good doctor is seeing a patient\h\h
i listen to people i allowed them to speak they\h
allowed me to speak i got pretty good info out\h\h
there to counter some of the misinformation that\h
was said or people believed initially though that\h\h
the criticism shifted from me being a pharma shill\h
me being indoctrinated to that my posture was bad\h\h
that I shrimp a lot and that I have gotten\h
extremely morbidly obese aka calling me fat\h\h
but it wasn't your run-of-the-mill body shaming it\h
was some kind of hyper masculine protestosterone\h\h
type ribbing and I say ribbing quite lightly\h
because they were being really mean about [Music]
it look I have definitely put on weight since\h
my boxing days in fact in order to have boxed\h\h
I lost about 30 lb because when you're training\h
two a days and burning 3,000 calories between\h\h
those two workouts and only consuming 2500 or\h
so you're losing weight every single day so\h\h
yes for my fight I got down to 182 lb but that\h
is not my normal walking around weight that was\h\h
extreme weight loss for my body so yes over\h
the last 2 years or so I probably gained 40\h\h
to 50 lbs where I would have liked to just put\h
on the 30 lb that I initially lost i'm under no\h\h
illusion that I've gained some weight i'm under\h
no illusion that father time catches us all and\h\h
that these grays are legit and that my empathetic\h
posture that Rib here loves is like this it's been\h\h
commented on Reddit before even on my curbside\h
consult videos unlike some people when they debate\h\h
someone else do stuff like this with their posture\h
I actually want to get into this kind of posture\h\h
where I'm looking to not overpower them i'm taller\h
i'm bigger i don't want to seem even larger so I\h\h
try to get even smaller and get on people's level\h
so yes you caught me i'm admitting it here i\h\h
gained weight i am not the healthiest I've ever\h
been and my posture sucks i will be losing that\h\h
weight but what what people will not be losing is\h
the record of the things that they have said to\h\h
me because while they have deleted their posts\h
I have screenshotted them and I'd like to read\h\h
some of them aloud right now first of all thank\h
you Amy you've deleted this tweet it went viral\h\h
got millions of views and you wrote "It's so scary\h
that doctors aren't taught nutrition like how can\h\h
you take their advice seriously when they live\h
such unhealthy personal lives?" interesting that\h\h
people think you have to be ripped in order to be\h
healthy first of all completely untrue second of\h\h
all as I said during the debate doctors make the\h
worst patients we're hypocrites but it doesn't\h\h
necessarily make the information that we're\h
providing be untrue i even said that to one\h\h
of the participants that hey doctors are humans\h
and just because they're not following their own\h\h
advice doesn't make it less factually accurate not\h
hating or anything but he looks older no no no no\h\h
i am older i've been on YouTube for almost\h
a decade that's facts not opinions and these\h\h
gray hairs are because of you doc you on a weight\h
gaining process yeah I'm bulking it's not summer\h\h
yet remember that was 3 months ago i could be\h
ripped right now i'm not but I could be he's at\h\h
least 20% body fat that's fat well like look when\h
we did our BMI video I was talking about how DEXA\h\h
scans are really accurate for measuring body fat\h
body impetence meters you could use a caliper but\h\h
the worst one is getting your body fat measurement\h
done via Twitter by a comment of a named Michael\h\h
Duggan thanks bro appreciate the inaccurate body\h
fat measurement oh Rob Smith an individual who I\h\h
actually met in the green room at Fox News Studios\h
cuz you know I used to do mornings with Maria\h\h
Barter Romo for like 3 years who was quite polite\h
to me and I was polite to him i was like "Oh cool\h\h
a nice guy getting along." And then he writes this\h
the most terrifying part of this is not that the\h\h
antivaxers who have valid and responsible concerns\h
about the current childhood vaccination schedule\h\h
industry is that Dr mike got fat poor one out for\h
his previous hotness folks it's gone sir that is\h\h
your opinion and you could actually enjoy that\h
opinion just kind of mean that you chose to put\h\h
it out on social media if you DM'd it to me\h
probably be less offended for some reason dr\h\h
mike looked disgusting gut protruding in his blue\h
scrubs at the debate very disrespectful they need\h\h
to look at those clips on I don't know if it's\h
Tik Tok or YouTube where people are like "Look\h\h
what I can look like when I sit in uncomfortable\h
position and look how much abs I have when I just\h\h
sit up or suck in my gut." He used to be called\h
the world's sexiest doctor no one called me that\h\h
people magazine called me hottest doctor alive\h
or sexiest doctor alive they didn't say worlds\h\h
they didn't talk about a geography and now I'm a\h
regular looking dude with poor posture you know\h\h
what spoiler alert i was a regularl looking dude\h
then with the same posture but slightly less body\h\h
fat so not much has changed when will they make\h
a vaccine for love handles yo I get that vaccine\h\h
their camera and lighting made you look fat nope\h
that was all my doing it's giving doughy and\h\h
impotent at least that's a medical comment medical\h
and cooking put together scrubs are not forgiving\h\h
i appreciate that and I definitely have gained\h
some weight and guess what i'm going to lose that\h\h
weight and I got to improve my cholesterol now\h
I'm doing psyllium husk decreasing my saturated\h\h
fat just trying to be healthier overall you\h
know what makes it hard to be healthy negative\h\h
comments online that's the unfortunate reality\h
according to gay Twitter he's a whale is that\h\h
like a bear but more buoyant i saw so many mean\h
comments towards the participants i'm not a fan\h\h
and it's not because I'm upy and I don't like\h
calling people names i'm from Brooklyn i get it\h\h
but calling people stupid while they may\h
feel good to you because ego boost to you\h\h
that you're smarter than them it's not valuable\h
nor is it truly fair because if you grew up with\h\h
certain circumstances around you or learning about\h
terrible things that happened to your culture you\h\h
may also end up believing inaccurate things and\h
that's not to say that everything people believe\h\h
in those situations is inaccurate there's always a\h
little bit of truth there maybe it's not the most\h\h
rational but it is what is most likely to happen\h
to the human mind the human mind is capable and\h\h
is very susceptible to emotional reasoning that is\h
why I try to get on the same page so that we can\h\h
decrease that emotional reasoning and perhaps get\h
to a more factual basis for our understanding and\h\h
that's where usually people start understanding\h
where I'm coming from okay sorry pause you've been\h\h
voted out by the majority thank you appreciate\h
that i also saw a lot of feedback of people\h\h
getting mad about the format me not being able\h
to fully fact check everything that the person\h\h
was saying but guess what if a patient comes in to\h
my exam room and is very passionate and is saying\h\h
a lot of things that perhaps aren't accurate or\h
they've been misled by someone I don't rush to\h\h
correct everything that's not a valuable strategy\h
in order to form a good doctor patient alliance\h\h
and in reality when you're practicing medicine\h
on a practical level you have time constraints\h\h
i don't have an hour with every patient that's\h
not realistic so the fact that things got cut\h\h
off and were incomplete was kind of similar\h
to what happens in real life and I will say\h\h
perhaps I didn't even feel that notion that a lot\h
of you have felt where every time I was making a\h\h
good point people voted me off i think what was\h
happening a lot of the time was if someone was\h\h
saying something that the audience wasn't feeling\h
like the participant across from me and they were\h\h
kind of just rambling they picked up their\h
flags and that's fair because it seemed like\h\h
the conversation was going nowhere if I answered\h
and the answer seemed to be complete and they\h\h
felt like okay we get what Dr mike is saying they\h
raised their flags i don't think they were trying\h\h
to actively silence me a I don't think they were\h
unified enough to have organized that and B I\h\h
think that they were there in enough good faith\h
that they wanted to hear me talk all that to say\h\h
I'm not defending the fact that I've gained some\h
weight that my posture is not great but please\h\h
for God's sake stop body shaming people it doesn't\h
help them and honestly it doesn't help you because\h\h
whatever false ego boost that you get in that\h
moment to make you feel better that I got to dig\h\h
on someone isn't really valuable it's not going\h
to make you happy and it's certainly not going\h\h
to help anyone lose weight so just cut it out and\h
speaking of body shaving folks on Reddit in the\h\h
past have accused me of being fat phobic and I\h
actually responded to that controversy you could\h\h
see that response here click here to check that\h
out and as always stay happy and healthy [Music]